Guide to the Lewis Gaston Leary Papers, 1790-1986
Lewis Gaston Leary papers 1790-1986
Leary, Lewis Gaston, 1906-
36 Linear Feet 29,802 Items
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library, Duke University
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The Lewis Gaston Leary Papers were received by the Rare Book, Manuscript, and Special Collections Libary as a gift in 1984-1986.
Biographical Note
An educator, writer, and critic, Leary taught at Duke and Columbia Universities, and the University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill.
Collection Overview
Chiefly notes, lectures, addresses, and articles on American writers, with an emphasis on early American literature, especially minor authors. Includes research materials on Philip Freneau, Parson Weems, and Henry D. Thoreau. The collection also contains correspondence, 1958-1985, and an autobiographical sketch by Leary. Most of this material is described in the container list.
Subject Headings
These are searchable subject entries for this collection. Performing a search on these subjects in the Duke University Libraries online catalog will bring up other related research materials.
Freneau, Philip Morin, 1752-1832
Leary, Lewis Gaston, 1906-
Thoreau, Henry David, 1817-1862
Weems, M. L. (Mason Locke), 1759-1825
American literature -- History and criticism
Contents of Collection
- Accession January 20, 1987
  - Biographical (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 1958-1979 (Box 2)
  - Correspondence, 1980-1985 (Box 3)
  - Twayne Author Series-Historical Guidelines, etc. (Box 4)
  - Twayne Author Series (Box 5)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 6)
  - Writings: The Early American Short Story (Box 7)
  - Writings: Harvestings (Box 8)
  - National Humanities Center Research, Beginnings of American Literature 1790-1820 (Box 9)
  - National Humanities Center Research,; Jeremy Belknap,; George Richards (Box 10)
  - National Humanities Center Research,; John Burk,; Abiel Holmes,; J. Lathrop,; Mercy Warren (Box 11)
  - Writings (Box 12)
  - Writings (Box 13)
  - Writings (Box 14)
  - Parson Weems-I (Box 5)
  - Parson Weems-II (Box 16)
  - American Literature-Early (Box 17)
  - American Literature-Notes, Lectures, etc. (Box 18)
  - American Literature/ Thoreau-Notes, Lectures, etc. (Box 19)
  - Paine, Robert Treat (Box 20)
  - American Literature- T. Tucker (Box 21)
  - American Literature- N. Tucker (Box 22)
  - American Literature (Box 23)
  - American Literature- Emerson I-Notes, Lectures (Box 24)
  - American Literatures- Emerson II-Notes, Lectures (Box 25)
  - W. N. Brown (Box 26)
  - American Literature, 1770-Lecture Notes (Box 27)
  - American Literature-Early (Box 28)
  - Freneau (Box 29)
  - American Literature- James F. Cooper-Lectures, Notes (Box 30)
  - American Literature-Notes, Lectures (Box 31)
  - American Literature-Notes, Lectures (Box 32)
  - Writings-Miscellaneous Authors (Box 33)
  - Writings-Miscellaneous Authors (Box 34)
  - Mark Twain,; Henry H. Rogers, Calendar 1900-1910 (Box 35A)
  - Writings: Reprints (Box 35B)
  - Mark Twain,; Henry H. Rogers, Calendar 1892-1899 (Box 35C)
  - Mark Twain,; Henry H. Rogers, Miscellany (Box 35D)
  - Writings-Miscellaneous Authors-Card File (Box 36)
  - Card File (Box 37)
  - Card File (Box 38)
  - Card File (Box 39)
  - Card File (Box 40)
  - Card File (Box 41)
  - Card File (Box 42)
  - Card File, Miscellaneous (Box 43)
  - Notes, Lectures, A-C (Box 44)
  - Notes, Lectures, D-G (Box 45)
  - Notes, Lectures, H-S (Box 46)